PAN HAO 潘昊

Email: panh09@sjtu.edu.cn | Phone: +86 15301451855

Biography

My name is Pan Hao (潘昊). I obtained my Ph.D. in Computer Science at the Shanghai Jiao Tong University in 2022, and my advisors are *Prof. Guangtao Xue* and *Assoc. Prof. Yi-Chao Chen*. During the doctoral studies, my main research interests focus on networked systems and spanned the areas of mobile computing, human-computer interaction and computer vision. To learn more about my research projects, please visit my homepage: https://haopan.netlify.app/.



Education

Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China

2016.9-2022.3

Ph.D. in Computer Science (School of Electronic Information and Electrical Engineering)

University of Electronic Science and Technology, Chengdu, China

2012.9-2016.7

B.S. in Information and Communication Engineering (Yingcai Honor College)

Selected Publication

Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=nuxKtp4AAAAJ&hl=en&oi=ao

Conference Papers:

- [1] <u>Hao Pan</u>, Lanqing Yang, Honglu Li, Yi-Chao Chen, Guangtao Xue. MagThief: Stealing Private App Usage Data on Mobile Devices via Built-in Magnetometer. Accepted by **IEEE SECON 2021**.
- [2] <u>Hao Pan</u>, Yi-Chao Chen, Qi Ye, Guangtao Xue. MagicInput: Training-free Multi-lingual Finger Input System using Data Augmentation based on MNISTs. Accepted by **ACM IPSN 2021**.
- [3] Yijie Li, Yi-Chao Chen, Xiaoyu Ji, <u>Hao Pan</u>, Lanqing Yang, Guangtao Xue, Jiadi Yu. "SCREENID: Enhancing QRCode Security by Fingerprinting Screens." **IEEE INFOCOM 2021.**
- [4] Lanqing Yang, Yi-Chao Chen, <u>Hao Pan</u>, Dian Ding, Guangtao Xue, Linghe Kong, Jiadi Yu, Minglu Li. "MagPrint: Deep Learning Based User Fingerprinting Using Electromagnetic Signals." **IEEE INFOCOM 2020.**
- [5] <u>Hao Pan</u>, Yi-Chao Chen, Lanqing Yang, Chuangwen You, Guangtao Xue, Xiaoyu Ji. "mQRCode: Secure QR Code Using Nonlinearity of Spatial Frequency in Light." **ACM MobiCom 2019.**
- [6] Yushi Cheng, Xiaoyu Ji, Wenyuan Xu, <u>Hao Pan</u>, Zhuangdi Zhu, Chuang-Wen You, Yi-Chao Chen, Lili Qiu. "MagAttack: Guessing Application Launching and Operation via Smartphone." **ACM AsiaCCS 2019.**
- [7] <u>Hao Pan</u>, Yi-Chao Chen, Guangtao Xue, Xiaoyu Ji. "Magnecomm: Magnetometer-based near-field communication." **ACM MobiCom 2017.**

Journal Papers:

- [1] Guangtao Xue, <u>Hao Pan</u>, Yi-Chao Chen, Xiaoyu Ji, Jiadi Yu. MagneComm+: Near-Field Electromagnetic Induction Communication with Magnetometer. **IEEE TMC 2021**.
- [2] Xiaoyu Ji, Yushi Cheng, Wenyuan Xu, Yuehan Chi, <u>Hao Pan</u>, Zhuangdi Zhu, Chuang-Wen You, Yi-Chao Chen, Lili Qiu. No Seeing is Also Believing: Electromagnetic-emission-based Application Guessing Attacks via Smartphones. **IEEE TMC 2021**.

PAN HAO 潘昊

Email: panh09@sjtu.edu.cn | Phone: +86 15301451855

Experience

Internship: Future Network Theory Lab, Huawei, Hong Kong

2015.8-2016.4

Lab Leader: Gong Zhang | Advisor: John C.S. Lui (ACM/IEEE Fellow), Yi Wang

Research Topic: Named data networking in vehicular ad hoc networks

StarBrige Program: Shanghai Research Lab, Microsoft Research Asia, Shanghai 2022.3-Now

Lab Leader and Advisor: Lili Qiu (ACM/IEEE Fellow)
Research Topic: Low Earth orbit satellite communication

Teaching

Computer Networks (XO33517), Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2019 Fall

Teaching Assistant | Lecturer: Guangtao Xue

Mobile Sensing and Computing (CS28014), Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2018 Fall

Teaching Assistant | Lecturer: Guangtao Xue

Honor and Award

2019	The Fifth Youth Innovation and Creativity Competition (STATE GRID)	Silver Award
2017	The Third Next Generation Internet Technology Innovation Competition (MOE)	National 1st Prize
2016	The Second Next Generation Internet Technology Innovation Competition (MOE)	National 1st Prize
2015	American Mathematical Modeling Competition (COMAP)	Meritorious Winner
2014	The 20th National Student Electronic Design Competition (MOE&MIIT)	Provincial 2nd Prize
2013-2015 UESTC People Scholarship		Second Prize

Skills

Programming: Python, C/C++ **Language:** English CET6 (510)